Finding Aid for John Engler Papers, 1968-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Engler Papers
1968-2003
Engler, John, 1948-
0434 Aa 2; UAm
Republican member of the Michigan state legislature (House and Senate, 1971-1990); governor of Michigan (1991-2003); active member of the Republican Governors' Association and the National Governors' Association. The Engler collection consists primarily of materials created and maintained by Governor Engler and his staff during the period when he was governor, 1991-2003. Other records include papers from his several terms in the Michigan House and the Michigan Senate. The collection includes papers files, photographs, sound recordings, videotapes, memorabilia, and some electronic files. The gubernatorial files are arranged mainly by unit or functional responsibility within the governor's office. These series are Executive Office, Communications Division, Legal Division, State Government Affairs, Legislative Affairs Division, Operations Division, External Affairs, Scheduling, Washington DC Office, and Office of the First Lady. Topics extensively documented include state welfare and school funding reform, reorganization of state boards and commissions, notably the restructuring of the Michigan Department of Natural Resources, and Republican party politics.
435 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection was the gift of Governor John Engler and came to the library in January, 2003. Donor no. 9332. Digital website records were captured using Teleport Pro 1.29 by Bentley Library staff on December 10, 2001. Digital images of presentation materials made by Bentley Library staff, February, 2004.
The collection is open to research. For some portions of the collection, original tapes are restricted and researchers are required to use DVDs.
When John Engler became Michigan's governor in 1991, he brought with him a classically conservative vision of a smaller, more efficient government, and of a state where taxes were lower, individual initiative was rewarded and business and opportunity could thrive. As Michigan's governor during the boom years of the 1990's, Engler led the state during a period of uncommon prosperity between 1991 and 2002. At the beginning of his tenure, however, Michigan's economy was less than ideal.
After defeating incumbent James Blanchard in 1990 in an upset election, Engler inherited a $1.8 billion deficit. He embarked on an effort to cut spending and taxes, and reorganized the government. His first term spending cuts were painful and controversial, and included cuts in welfare for childless adults, state mental-health facilities, and arts programs. In the aftermath, Engler was widely viewed as a cold-hearted bureaucrat who was more concerned with balancing budgets than with the pain and suffering of poor people. But as it turned out, Michigan was on the vanguard of a national movement to change welfare, putting more focus on work. By the time Engler sought re-election in 1994, none of the three Democrats seeking the nomination proposed a return to the General Assistance Program.
In his effort to achieve greater efficiency in state government, Engler presided over the most dramatic restructuring of state government in a generation. He eliminated entire departments and abolished dozens of boards and commissions. He pushed the power of the Executive Branch to the fullest extent permitted by the Michigan Constitution to implement his reorganizations.
In 1995 Engler split the Michigan Department of Natural Resources into a parks and recreation-oriented DNR, and a new Department of Environmental Quality, charged with monitoring pollution and public health. The changes were controversial because critics claimed they interfered with citizen oversight.
He also created the Michigan Jobs Commission and later, the Michigan Economic Development Corporation. With an aggressive business attraction strategy and a locally driven job training system, Michigan managed to attract many new job-creating businesses. In fact, Michigan earned the prestigious "Governor's Cup" -- representing the nation's number one state for new factories and expansion projects -- a record-setting four years in a row (1997-2000).
But education reform was Engler's top priority. He led the campaign to win citizen approval for Proposal A -- a 1994 ballot initiative that radically changed the way Michigan's public schools are funded. By loosening the connection between local property taxes and school funding, he aimed to make per-student funding more fair. And even though Proposal A slashed homeowners local property school tax rates by an average of 45%, school spending grew during Engler's tenure, from about $8 billion annually to nearly $12 billion--benefiting from booming tax revenues during the bountiful 1990's.
Engler also championed school choice, charter schools and more competition as part of his plan to help Michigan schools improve. His administration focused on high standards, more accountability, tough tests, improved safety and more discipline to help Michigan's students learn better.
Engler also saw the power of technology to create jobs and better people's lives. As the first governor to have a website, he pushed for increased availability of high-speed broadband Internet, and supported the creation of the nation's first on-line cybercourts. He also introduced a program to distribute laptop computers to more than 88,000 K-12 teachers statewide.
Engler was Chairman of the Republican Governors' Association in 1996 and of the National Governor's Association July 2001 to July 2002. He was a member of the Advisory Board of the Republican National Leadership Council and was considered a top-seeded candidate for Bob Dole's Vice Presidential running-mate in 1996.
John Engler was born October 12, 1948, the oldest of Mathias and Agnes Engler's seven children. His parents raised cattle on 900 acres near Beal City, Michigan and John majored in agricultural economics at Michigan State University. As a class project for a political science class, Engler wrote a paper outlining his strategy for winning a Republican primary against an incumbent for a seat in the state legislature. In 1970, before graduating, he enlisted the help of his friend, sophomore Dick Posthumus, and put his plan into action. He won the primary, and the general election to become, at age 22, the youngest Michigan legislator. Indeed, in his thirty-year political career, John Engler never lost an election.
The Republicans were the minority party in the Michigan House when Engler set out in 1971, although Republican William Milliken controlled the governor's office. Engler served eight years in the House and twelve years in the Michigan Senate, rising to become Senate Majority Leader in 1984 after leading an intense effort to tip the balance toward the GOP. While serving in the legislature, Engler attended law school part-time and received his degree from Thomas Cooley Law School in 1981.
He married fellow lawmaker Colleen House in 1975, though they divorced in 1986. He wed again to attorney Michelle DeMunbrun in 1990. They are the parents of triplet daughters, Margaret, Hannah and Madeleine, born November 13, 1994, just days after his reelection to a second gubernatorial term.
Summary Contents List
Pre-gubernatorial Career, 1968-1990 (18.5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 2-20)
Desk Calendars, 1972-1990 except 1975, 1978 and 1983 (1 lin. ft.) (Box 2)
House Career, 1968-1978 (3 lin. ft.) (Boxes 3-5)
Press Releases and News Clippings, 1970-1978 (1.8 lin. ft.)
Miscellaneous, 1971-1977 (0.2 lin. ft.)
Campaigns, 1968-1976 (1 lin. ft.)
Senate Career, 1979-1990 (14.5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 6-20)
Press Releases and News Clippings, 1979-1989 (1.5 lin. ft.)
Campaigns, 1978-1986 (2 lin. ft.)
Speeches, 1986-1990 (1 lin. ft.)
Topical, 1983-1987 (6.2 lin. ft.)
Correspondence A-Z, 1986 (0.5 lin. ft.)
Personal, 1979-1985 (0.4 lin. ft.)
Michigan Senatorial Trust, 1981-1985, bulk 1981-1982 (1 lin. ft.)
Miscellaneous, 1979-1990 (1.9 lin. ft.)
Gubernatorial Papers, 1970-2003 (411 lin. ft.) (Boxes 1, 21-433)
Executive Office, 1970-2002, bulk 1990-2002 (44 lin. ft.) (Boxes 21-64)
Governor's Own Office, 1970-2002 (16.9 lin. ft.) (Boxes 21-37)
Governor's Executive Assistant, 1991-2002 (7.5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 38-45)
Office of the Chief of Staff, 1987-2002 (15.8 lin. ft.) (Boxes 46-62)
Audio-Visual Media, 1995-2001 (1 lin. ft.) (Box 63)
Career history, 1990-2002 (1 lin. ft.) (Box 64)
Communications Division, 1991-2002 (99 lin. ft.) (Box 65-166)
Press Releases, 1991-2002 (6.2 lin. ft.) (Box 65-71)
News Clips, 1991-2002 (4 lin. ft.) (Boxes 71-75)
Speechwriter John Nevin, 1991-2002 (10.3 lin. ft.) (Boxes 75-85)
Newspapers and Magazines, 1970-2002 (0.5 lin. ft.) (Box 85)
Communications Director, Speechwriter and Administration Historian Gleaves Whitney, 1991-2002 (25.8 lin. ft.) (Boxes 86-112)
Press Officer, John Truscott 1991-2001 (1 lin. ft.) (Boxes 112-113)
Speeches, 1991-2002 (21.5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 113-134)
Video Tapes, 1989-2002 (26 lin. ft., approx. 850 tapes) (Boxes 135-160)
Audio Cassette Tapes, 1991-2000 (3 lin. ft., approx. 250 tapes) (Boxes 161-165)
Reel-to-Reel Tape, Slides and Photographs (0.5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 165-166)
Legal Division, 1991-2002 (Boxes 167-187)
Executive Orders, 1991-2002 (5.5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 167-172)
Drafts never issued
Executive Directives, Proclamations and Special Election Calls, 1991-2002 (0.9 lin. ft.) (Boxes 172-173)
Executive clemency--Pardons and commutations (1.9 lin. ft.) (Boxes 173-175)
Judicial Appointments, 1991-2002 (1.1 lin. ft.) (Boxes 175-176)
Litigation, 1990-2001 (3.8 lin. ft) (Boxes 176-181)
Topical Files, 1985-2002 (1.7 lin. ft.) (Boxes 181-183)
Indians--State Tribal Affairs, 1993-2002 (1 lin. ft.) (183-184)
Correspondence of Legal Counsel and Deputy Legal Counsel, 1991-2002 (2 lin. ft.) (Boxes 183-186)
Redistricting (Box 186)
Judicial Appointments, 1991-2002) (0.5 lin. ft.) (Box 187)
State Government Affairs, 1991-2002 (52 lin. ft.) (Boxes 189-240.)
Policy Division (Predecessor of State Government Affairs) and Senior Policy Advisor Dennis Schornack, 1990-2002 (5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 189-193)
Office of the Director, 1991-2002 (22.8 lin. ft.) (Boxes 194-216)
Office of the Policy Coordinator for Agriculture--Brad Deacon, 1996-1998 (0.3 lin. ft.) (Box 216)
Office of the Policy Coordinator for Career Development, Civil Rights and Disabilities--Lisa Splawn and Kim Harding, 1993-2002 (0.3 lin. ft.) (Box 217)
Office of the Policy Coordinator for Military and Veterans' Affairs--Steve Kozera, 1992-1999 (0.5 lin. ft.) (Box 217)
Office of the Policy Coordinator for Criminal Justice--Tom Ginster, 1991-1998 (2.8 lin. ft.) (Boxes 217-220)
Office of the Policy Coordinator for Environment and Infrastructure, 1991-2002 (8.6 lin. ft.) (Boxes 220-229)
Office of the Policy Coordinator for Education--Scott Jenkins, 1994-2001 (1.2 lin. ft.) (Boxes 229-230)
Office of the Policy Coordinator for Human Services, 1991-2002 (6.8 lin. ft.) (Boxes 230-238)
Special Projects Policy Advisor--Don Allen, 1990-2002 (2.4 lin. ft.) (Boxes 238-240)
Legislative Affairs Division, 1991-2002 (39.3 lin. ft.) (Boxes 241-280)
Public Acts and Vetoes, 1991-2002 (39.1 lin. ft.)
JE Issues, 1992-2002 (0.2 lin. ft.)
Campaigns, Inaugurations, Special Projects (Operations Division), 1971-1999, bulk 1987-1999 (33.7 lin. ft.) (Boxes 281-314)
Engler for Governor 1990, 1971-1990 (5.6 lin. ft.) (Boxes 281-286)
Transition Team, 1972-1992, bulk 1990-1991 (3.3 lin. ft.) (Boxes 188, 286-288)
Inaugural Planning--LeAnne Redick (Wilson), 1990-1991 (0.5 lin. ft.) (Box 289)
Bush/Quayle '92 Campaign--Dave Bertram, 1992 (1 lin. ft.) (Boxes 289-290)
Proposal A, 1993-1994 (0.8 lin. ft.) (Boxes 290-291)
Michigan All-STAR Team for School and Tax Reform--Kathy DeGrow and Nancy Harrison, 1993-1999 (0.4 lin. ft.) (Box 291)
Right Plan for Michigan--Nancy Harrison, 1994-1999 (0.3 lin. ft.) (Box 291)
Engler for Governor 1994, 1993-1994 (3.5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 292-295)
Secchia Commission--Chris Becker and Brett Marr (1.5 lin. ft.) (Boxes 295-296)
Inaugural Planning--Shelly Stahl, 1994-1995 (0.8 lin. ft.) (Box 297)
Dole/Kemp '96 and other 1996 campaigns--Margaret Dwyer (2.2 lin. ft.) (Boxes 297-299)
Engler for Governor 1998, 1997-1998 (8.7 lin. ft.) (Boxes 300-309)
Inaugural Planning, 1998-1999 (0.6 lin. ft.) (Box 309)
Nancy Harrison Projects, 1990-1992 (0.4 lin. ft.) (Box 309-310)
Photographs, 1990-1996 (0.1 lin. ft.) (Box 310)
Video, 1990-1999 (3 lin. ft.) (Boxes 311-313)
Audiotape (1 lin. ft.) (Box 314)
External Affairs (Public Affairs), 1991-2001 (1.9 lin. ft.) (Boxes 315-316)
Rusty Hills Papers, 1991-2001 (0.8 lin. ft.)
Tim Ward Papers, 1996-1997 (0.9 lin. ft.)
Constituent Services Correspondence F-J, 1999 (0.2 lin. ft.)
Scheduling Office, 1991-2002 (76 lin. ft.) (Boxes 317-392)
Schedules, 1991-2002 (75 lin. ft.)
Master Datebooks, 1991-2001 (1 lin. ft.)
Washington DC Office, 1991-2002 (12.6 lin. ft.) (Boxes 393-405)
Governor's Correspondence, 1992-2002 (1 lin. ft.)
Chronological Letters and Memoranda, 1991-2001 (1 lin. ft.)
Office of the Director--LeAnne Redick (Wilson), 1991-2001 (3 lin. ft.)
Federal Legislative Liaison--Debbie Marshall, 1993-2001 (1.3 lin. ft.)
State of Michigan Washington Report, 1991-2002(0.3 lin. ft.)
National Governors' Association, 1999-2002 (5.1 lin. ft.)
Republican Governors' Association, 1992-2001 (0.9 lin. ft.)
Office of the First Lady, Michelle Engler, 1990-2002 (17.4 lin. ft.) (Boxes 406-423)
Boards, 1991-2002 (3.6 lin. ft.)
Miscellaneous Organizations and Projects, 1991-2002 (1 lin. ft.)
Correspondence, 1991-2002 (1 lin. ft.)
Events, 1991-2002 (7 lin. ft.)
National Governors' Association, 1990-2002 (0.7 lin. ft.)
President's Summit for America's Future, Philadelphia, PA, Apr. 27-29, 1997 (0.2 lin. ft.)
Speeches, 1991-2002 (2.1 lin. ft.)
VIP Files, 1991-2002 (0.5 lin. ft.)
Biographical and Miscellaneous, 1990-2001 (0.8 lin. ft.)
Photographs, 1990-2000 (0.5 lin. ft.)
Michigan State Departments, 1989-2002 (9.3 lin. ft.) (Box 424-433)
Electronic Media, 1994-2002 (Box 1)
Background and compiled information (Box 1)
Memorabilia and realia, 1968-2002 (Box 434-435)
The John Engler papers are the most important source available for the study of Michigan's state government from 1991 to 2002. The collection is particularly strong on the topics of welfare and school funding reform, state government reorganization and the rising impact of the National Governors' Association in state and national politics. Engler's efforts to attract commerce to Michigan are also well-documented. The materials are arranged into two main subgroups: Pre-gubernatorial Papers and Gubernatorial Papers. The bulk of the material relates to Engler's gubernatorial career, therefore, the analysis that follows focuses primarily on this subgroup.
The materials in the "Gubernatorial Papers" subgroup are arranged according to the offices and subdivisions of the governor's office that created them. This means that the governor's speeches and press releases, for example, may be found within a grouping or "series" called "Communications Division," within the "Gubernatorial" subgroup, while legislative histories for various public acts may be found within the "Legislative Affairs" series.
While some kinds of documents were produced uniquely by one division, other kinds were produced in several divisions of the governor's office. The governor's correspondence, for example, was drafted and approved by several different staff members. Letters to important business and political leaders may be found within the "Executive Office" series, the "State Government Affairs" series, and the "Washington DC Office" series in particular. There no comprehensive chronological correspondence file.
In using the collection, the researcher should think functionally and ask who would have created the information sought. For example, the policy advisors in the State Government Affairs Division created individual topical files which gathered together correspondence and research materials to support briefing memoranda which they presented to the governor, while the speechwriters in the Communications Division often gathered different types of materials to help them shape the presentation of the same policies to the public.
Subjects:
Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Educational change--Michigan.; Engler, John, 1948-; Environmental protection--Michigan.; Family policy--Michigan.; Governors--Michigan.; Michigan. Governor (1991-2003: Engler); Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives.; Michigan. Legislature. Senate.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1991-2000.; Michigan--Politics and government--2001-2010.; National Governors' Association.; Public welfare administration--Michigan.; Republican Party (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Engler, John, 1948-; Michigan--Politics and government.; Republican Party (Mich.); Governors--Michigan.; Political elections--Michigan.; Politics and government--Michigan.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Engler, John, 1948-; Michigan. Governor (1991-2003: Engler); Michigan--Politics and government.; Republican Party (Mich.)
Contributors:
Engler, Michelle.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Pre-gubernatorial Career, 1968-1990; 18.5 linear feet
  - Desk Calendars
    - 1972-1990 except 1975, 1978, 1983, 1 linear feet (Box 2)
  - House Career, 1968-1978; 3 linear feet
    John Engler was a member of the Michigan House of Representatives from 1971 through 1978 and the documents here largely fall between these dates. This subseries consists primarily of press releases and newspaper clippings detailing his activities within the state legislature. Included also are files relating to his various election campaigns.
    - Press Releases and News Clippings, 1970-1978; 1.8 linear feet
      - Albosta, Don (D) vs. Elford Cederberg (R) 10th Michigan Congressional District, 1978; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - District Press
        - Campaign, 1976 (Box 3)
        - Carson City Gazette, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
        - Central Michigan University Life, 1971-1978 (Box 3)
        - Clare Sentinel, 1971-1978 (Box 3)
        - Daily Record-Leader, Alma, 1971-1976; 2 folders (Box 3)
        - Daily Times News, 1971-1976; 5 folders (Box 3)
        - Edmore Times, 1971-1978; 2 folders (Box 3)
        - Farwell News, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
        - Gratiot County Herald, 1971-1978 (Box 3)
        - Greenville Daily News, 1971-1978 (Box 4)
        - Howard City Record, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
        - Lakeview Enterprise, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
        - Morning Sun, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
        - Others, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
        - Shepherd Argus, 1971-1978; 3 folders (Box 4)
        - Weidman Messenger, 1971-1975 (Box 4)
      - House Republican Office Press Releases, 1970-1978; 3 folders (Box 4)
      - Office of John Engler, State Representative, Press Releases, 1971-1978 (Box 4)
      - Outside District Press Various Newspapers, 1973-1978; 5 folders (Box 4)
      - Senatorial 36th District Campaign
        - Primary Race vs. John Toepp, March-August 1978; 2 folders (Box 4)
        - Primary Victory, August 1978 (Box 4)
        - General Election vs. John A. Jones, August-November 1978 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1977; 0.2 linear feet
      - Commencement Addresses, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
      - Expense Report, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
      - Intergovernmental Personnel Program Application, 1977 (Box 4)
      - Occasional Speeches of John M. Engler, 1971-1976 (Box 4)
      - Publications, 1977 (Box 4)
      - Republican Legislative Dinner, 1975 (Box 4)
      - White House Youth Conference, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Campaigns, 1968-1976; 1 linear feet
      - Election: Engler, Matt vs. Russell Strange, 1968 (Box 5)
      - Election, 1970
        - Ballenger, William S., speeches (Box 5)
        - Bumper Stickers (Box 5)
        - Campaign Management Booklets, 1962-1970 (Box 5)
        - Congratulations (Box 5)
        - Finance, Receipts and Expenses, 2 folders (Box 5)
        - Opposition Research -- Joe DeBolt (Box 5)
        - Opposition Research -- Russell Strange (Box 5)
        - Strategy materials (Box 5)
      - Election, 1972
        - Advertising and Flyers (Box 5)
        - Clips (Box 5)
        - Congratulations (Box 5)
        - Correspondence and endorsements (Box 5)
        - Opposition Research -- Dick Allen, clips (Box 5)
        - Opposition Research -- Dick Allen, mailings (Box 5)
        - Reapportionment (Box 5)
        - Vote information (Box 5)
      - Election, 1974
        - Clips, ads and other materials (Box 5)
        - House, Colleen (Box 5)
          (Engler's first wife's campaign for a House seat)
        - Opposition Research -- James Dickinson (Box 5)
        - Taylor, Cliff for Congress (Box 5)
      - Election, 1976
        - Clips, ads and other materials, 2 folders (Box 5)
        - Correspondence (Box 5)
        - Expenses and receipts (Box 5)
        - Opposition Research -- Bill Odykirk (Box 5)
        - Planning (Box 5)
        - Political Reform Act (Box 5)
        - Strategy (Box 5)
        - Target '76 Leadership Seminar (Box 5)
  - Senate Career, 1979-1990; 14.5 linear feet
    Engler was a member of the Michigan State Senate from 1979 through 1990. This series is further subdivided into the following subseries: Press releases and clippings; Campaigns; Speeches; Topical Files; Correspondence; Personal; Michigan Senatorial Trust; and Miscellaneous.
    - Press Releases and News Clippings, 1979-1989; 1.5 linear feet
      - 1979
        - Clips, 1979 (Box 6)
        - Columns, 1979 (Box 6)
        - Media List and Radio, 1979 (Box 6)
        - Press Releases, 1979 (Box 6)
      - 1980
        - Clips, 1980 (Box 6)
        - Press Releases, 1980 (Box 6)
      - 1981
        - Clips, 1981 (Box 6)
          (Benzie Record Patriot, Big Rapids Pioneer, Cadillac Evening News, Central Michigan University Life, Detroit Free Press, Detroit News, Evart Review, Farwell News and Review, Midland Daily News, Mt. Pleasant Morning Sun, Traverse City Record Eagle, Miscellaneous)
        - Press Releases, 1981 (Box 6)
      - 1982
        - Clips, 1982; 2 folders (Box 6)
        - Press Releases, 1982 (Box 6)
      - 1983
        - Clips, 1983 (Box 6)
          (Big Rapids Pioneer, Clare Cleaver, Clare Sentinel, Central Michigan University Life, Coleman Tribune, Detroit Free Press, Detroit News, Evart Review, Gratiot County Herald, Midland Daily News)
        - Clips, 1983 (Box 6)
          (Mt. Pleasant Morning Sun, Osceola County Herald, Shepherd Argus, Miscellaneous, Newsletters)
        - Press Releases, 1983 (Box 6)
      - 1984
        - Clips, 1984 (Box 6)
          (Big Rapids Pioneer, Clare Cleaver, Clare Sentinel, Central Michigan University Life, Coleman Tribune, Detroit Free Press, Detroit News, Evart Review, Gratiot County Herald, Lansing State Journal, Midland Daily News
        - Clips, 1984 (Box 6)
        - Press Releases, 1984 (Box 6)
      - 1985
        - Clips, 1985 (Box 6)
          (Big Rapids Pioneer, Clare Cleaver, Central Michigan University Life, Coleman Tribune, Detroit Free Press, Detroit News, Evart Review, Grand Rapids Press)
        - Clips, 1985 (Box 6)
          (Gratiot County Herald, Lansing State Journal, Midland Daily News, Mt. Pleasant Morning Sun, Osceola County Herald, Shepherd Argus, Miscellaneous, Newsletters)
        - Press Releases, 1985 (Box 6)
      - 1986
        - Clips, 1986 (Box 6)
          (Big Rapids Pioneer, Clare Cleaver, Central Michigan University Life, Coleman Tribune, Detroit Free Press, Detroit News, Evart Review)
        - Clips, 1986 (Box 7)
          (Grand Rapids Press, Gratiot County Herald, Lansing State Journal, Midland Daily News, Mt. Pleasant Morning Sun, Osceola County Herald, Shepherd Argus, Miscellaneous, Newsletters)
        - Press Releases, 1986 (Box 7)